

Victor Wang Software Engineer

About me

When I found a hobby in hiking, I finished the Inca Trail. When I found a market opportunity, I started a business. And when I created my first application, I found a passion in programming. I've gone from Business Development to Web Development after eight years of being a successful sales leader. As a developer, I apply the same level of focus, resourcefulness and ambition to my work as I have with my accomplishments. I'm always seeking ways to improve and I'm hungry to learn more.

Contact

(203) 848 - 9965

mailbox.vmw@gmail.com

Philadelphia, PA

Links

victor-wang-14890753

v-wang

Personal site (in progress)

Education

Saint Joseph's University Bachelor of Science (B.S.), Biology (2008-2012)

- Achievement Award Scholarship
- United Scholars Grant
- New Member Educator of Sigma Phi Epsilon

Skills / Languages

JavaScript

React.js

Node.js

- Git / GitHub
- API integrations
- Heroku
- CRM development
- Growth hacking
- Conversational Mandarin

Experience

• HTML / CSS

Vice President, Partnerships

Peergrade Inc. - Boston, MA / Copenhagen, Denmark (Mar 2018 - Oct

- Built and lead the sales organization from the ground up and supported sales operations
- Increased monthly recurring revenue by 152% within one year (2018-2019)
- Lead the launch of Eduflow, a new SaaS training tool, at the end of 2019 and identified and secured early adopters
- Grew monthly active users from 4,000 to 239,000 since the launch of
- Recently worked on strategies to pivot company focus towards new verticals such as enterprise training
- Regularly meet with academic and enterprise leadership, including CTO's, CIO's and Department Chairs

Vice President, Sales

Swing Education - San Mateo, CA (Apr 2017 - Oct 2017)

- Secured school partners within 5-months and built a pipeline of roughly 600 partners
- Transitioned the organization to a new CRM and lead both deployment and implementation to help support initial efforts in marketing and sales
- Developed and lead a team of six contractors, from training to establishing sales strategy and standard operating procedures
- Attended conferences and began an aggressive events program to drive new and existing relationships

Vice President, Business Development The New York Code + Design Academy - New York, NY (Nov 2015 -Nov 2016)

- Created and launched Generation Code, an innovative computer science education program for public and private schools throughout the US
- Generated nearly \$200,000 in revenue within 4 months of launch
- Lead full partnership cycles including outreach, contract negotiations, execution and client services
- Determined strategic direction and identified key partnerships
- Maintained an accurate pipeline and worked with C-Level executives on revenue forecasts

Director of Admissions

The New York Code + Design Academy - New York, NY (Oct 2014 - Nov 2015)

- Successfully lead sales team to increase student enrollment and revenue
- Developed and implemented strategies to retarget and segment markets which helped pave way to our acquisition by Strayer Education (currently SEI)
- Developed structure and standard operating procedures for the Admissions team
- Maintained a healthy flow of qualified applicants to maximize enrollments
- Managed the day to day operations of the Admissions team